(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T23:55:10.536239",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
TERIMA KASIH!
Thank you!
BERKAT KALIAN, KAMI BISA BERSINAR
Thanks to you, we can shine.
TERIMA KASIH UDAH BIKIN STAGE INI & HIDUP KAMI LEBIH BERWARNA!
Thank you for making this stage & our lives more colorful!
Terima Kasih!!
Thank you!!
TERIMA KASIH BANYAK!!!!!
Thank you so much!!!!!
Terima Kasih!! Kalian Semua Keren BGT!!
Thank you!! You all are super cool!!
Terima Kasih!!
Thank you!!
Makasih ya!
Thank you!
terima kasih
thank you
Ayo mulai!!
Let's begin!!
CHROMATIC FUTURE
[Title: CHROMATIC FUTURE]
Welcome to Chromatic Future.
身も心も
Body and soul...
この手で make you mine
I'll make you mine with these hands.
Wow wow wow
oh baby, i need you, i need you ずっと…
Oh baby, I need you, I need you forever...
君を視るたび 上書きされてく 欲望に
Every time I look at you, my desire is overwritten
重なる eyes, eyes, eyes
With our overlapping eyes, eyes, eyes,
胸打つ your smile, smile, smile
And your heart-striking smile, smile, smile.
ねぇ その姿 形 全てが 拍車掛けてく
Hey, your figure, your shape, everything spurs it on,
恋から愛、愛、愛
From liking to love, love, love,
毎秒 おかしくなってく
I'm going crazy second by second.
手を伸ばせば もう届く距離
If I reach out, you are within reach,
危険な “A to Z” 試したい
I want to try a dangerous "A to Z."
穏やかに 恋したい どんなシーンも 私に見せて
I want to love you gently, show me every scene of you.
このまま stay by my side
Stay by my side just like this,
“どこにも行かないで”
"Don't go anywhere."
aww！ 100% 純粋な愛だから
Aww! Because it's 100% pure love,
ねぇ、いいでしょ？
Hey, is that okay?
止められない感情 その腕で抱き締めてよ
Hold this unstoppable feeling in your arms.
aww！ 遠くからじゃ嫌
Aww! I don't want it from afar,
ずっともっと近くで 認め合いたい
I want to accept each other much closer.
暴れ狂う衝動 持て余すだけならツライ
This raging urge is painful if left unused.
hey me！ what's wrong with me？
Hey me! What's wrong with me?
何も問題ない 普通だし
There's nothing wrong, I'm normal,
君の全部知りたい
I just want to know everything about you.
i do need you 今すぐ
I do need you right now.
最初は “声を聴く” それだけでよかった
At first, just hearing your voice was enough,
だけど次第に Why？ 我が儘になった
But gradually, why? I became selfish.
誰かに笑いかける その仕草に
Seeing you smiling at someone else,
苛立ち隠せない 自分に気づいた
I realized I couldn't hide my irritation.
「独り占めしたい」
"I want you all to myself."
いっそ、鎖に繋いで
I'd rather chain you up.
二人きりの部屋 至近距離
Just the two of us in a room, close distance,
行動 発言 監視したい
I want to monitor your actions and words.
頬を寄せて眠りたい その吐息感じさせて
I want to sleep with our cheeks together, let me feel your breath.
永遠に stay by your side
Stay by your side forever,
“どこにも行かせない”
"I won't let you go anywhere."
aww！ 100% 私だけに依存して
Aww! Depend on 100% of me,
ねぇ、いいでしょ？
Hey, is that okay?
黒く染まる愛憎 まるごと受け止めてよ
Accept all of this love and hate dyed in black.
aww！ 私、変かしら？
Aww! Am I strange?
だとしても引き返せない 歪んでく world
Even so, I can't turn back in this distorting world.
暴れ狂う衝動 歯止め効かせない 絶対
I'll never put a brake on this raging impulse.
hey me！ what's wrong with me？
Hey me! What's wrong with me?
何も問題ない 普通だし
There's nothing wrong, I'm normal,
君の全部知りたい
I just want to know everything about you.
i do need you 今すぐ
I do need you right now.
目を閉じたら
If I close my eyes,
とめどない恋愛観 触れたいの
I want to touch this endless view of love.
boy, you 私の…私だけの…
Boy, you are mine... only mine...
このまま stay by my side
Stay by my side just like this,
“二度と離れないで”
"Don't ever leave me again."
aww！ 100% 純粋な愛だから
Aww! Because it's 100% pure love...
らら れれ...
Lala Lele...
止められない感情
Unstoppable emotions...
その手で抱きしめてよ
...hold me tight with those hands.
あぁ 遠くからじゃなく
Ah, not from far away...
ずっともっと近くで
...but always much closer...
認め合いたいよ
...I want us to accept each other.
働く少女よ
O working girls...
持て余すようならストライク
...if it's too much to handle, strike!
エイミー what's wrong with me?
Amy, what's wrong with me?
なんともないない フトダシ
Nothing's wrong, wrong, futodashi.
ナイメイ 指の隙間締め付けたい
Naimei, I want to tighten the gaps of fingers.
アージュ ニュウ セイ シリタイ
Aaju nyuu sei shiritai.
アージュ ニジュウ イマ スグ
Aaju nijuu, right now!
Oh baby, I need you, I need you ずっと
Oh baby, I need you, I need you forever.
[Title: Hololive Indonesia 3D Live]
見えるなら今だよ
If you can see it, now is the time!
勝利を願っちゃって
Wish for victory...
叫んじゃって!
...and scream out!
デイドリーム
Daydream...
騒ごう!
...let's make some noise!
突き進めばオッケー!
If we push forward, we'll be okay!
Anyaはだんだん眠くなる
Anya is getting sleepier and sleepier.
Anya催眠にかかる
Anya falls into hypnosis.
体も心も言うこときかない
Neither body nor mind will listen.
ナイスな夜を全部無視したい
I want to ignore all the nice nights.
Harap bersiap, standby ya!
Please get ready, standby!
もう正直あきあきなんだよ
Honestly, I'm already tired of it.
Tak usah cemas, sanggup kuatasi, mewarnai hari ini!
Don't worry, I can handle it, coloring today!
Nanti kita nyusul Zeta
Later we will catch up to Zeta...
mereka yang mau berhenti
...those who want to stop.
Aku tidak perlu keberuntungan, karena ku berlari!
I don't need luck, because I'm running!
Cepat tunjukkan kekuatan!
Quickly, show your strength!
Day by day, shoudashi ara ara, yaritai koto zenbu pin wo sashita
Day by day, showing off, ara ara, putting a pin in everything I want to do.
Waratte kuretat te ii jan
It's fine if you laugh at me.
いつでもどこでも
Anytime and anywhere...
Victory to the world, say!
Tunjukkan pesonamu dan kekuatan kita
Show your charm and our strength...
kita pasti akan menang, ayo!
...we will definitely win, let's go!
見て、見て、見て、横の今日!
Look, look, look at today!
Zeta、いらっしゃって!
Zeta, please come!
Lampu menyala di malam hari
The lights are shining at night...
santai saja ku tak peduli
...I'm just relaxing and I don't care.
Coba singkirkan Zeta
Try to get rid of Zeta...
koko wa doko, game over!
...where is this? Game over!
Mimpi indah yang kudapat
The beautiful dream I got...
membuatku semakin kuat
...makes me stronger.
Fokus terus berlari, melewati semua rintangan!
Focus on running, passing through all obstacles!
Ayo menari, one, two, three!
Come on and dance, one, two, three!
Sinar terang yang indah, a trip to trip!
The beautiful bright light, a trip to trip!
Kita selalu bersama
We're always together...
a-re-re, tidak mau menyerah!
...oh my, we don't want to give up!
Nai nai, nei nei, fighting kanagara
Lan lan lan la, journal no senbu wa kyan-sen
Lan lan lan la, canceling all journals.
Naisa se, yamenaisa!
Make it nice, don't stop!
Sore ga watashi no kyun faito ni naru to mo shirazu ni ne
Without even knowing that it would become my heart-throbbing fight.
Victory to the world, say!
Tomo ni sukuru tatakitai na, atsuki de tamannaka o
Want to strike together, hit it at the hot center.
Kokochi i no kyou no kyou
Comfortable today of today.
Kimi somachatte!
You, get dyed!
Kami Flow! Ayo ngebanyol!
God Flow! Let's banter!
Oi! Oi! Oi! Oi!
Ayo, Anya juga!
Come on, Anya too!
Ayo, Reine mana suaranya?!
Come on, Reine, where's your voice?!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
BPM makin tinggi!
BPM is getting higher!
Hei, ku takkan goyah!
Hey, I won't waver!
Day by day, mogutte, mada mada
Day by day, diving, not yet...
Moridako shi ni akaunto totte
...create an account for Moridako.
Waratte kuretat te ii jan
It's fine if you laugh at me.
i-i-ja to-ra-mi-na i-zu-ka
Champion yobas dake
Just call me champion!
Victory to the world, say!
Zettai oinuku yo, ano hi karude yukidou o
I will definitely overtake you, that path on that day...
Wasurerarenai hodo no
...to the point I can't forget.
Shouri wo negachatte!
Wish for victory!
Kyouchi wo ikou, jiji-i!
Let's go to that state, old man!
Siapa di sini yang lelah...
Who here is tired...
dengan kehidupan?
...of life?
Aku! Aku!
Me! Me!
Kalau capek...
If you're tired...
enaknya gimana nih, HoloHero?
...what should we do, HoloHero?
Malas saja!
Just be lazy!
Cakep!
Cool!
Bukannya sudah biasa...
Isn't it already normal...
di titik lelah kecewa...
...at the point of tired disappointment...
saat dunia tak berjalan semestinya
when the world doesn't go the way you want it to
oh, oh
mungkin sudahlah saatnya
and maybe now is just the perfect time
kau coba lepaskan saja
to let it go and just unwind
tak perlu tanya mengapa lagi
there's no need to ask why ever again
jika memang
just let it go,
jawaban tak kau dapatkan
the answer you've been looking for
jangan tangisi
no need to be sad about it,
coba lalui teka-tekinya
just try to get through your day
relakan lah
just let it go,
karena pada akhirnya
then maybe in the end you'll know
kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
you got what it takes to get through the ache and still win the day
dahlah saja, oh, dahlah saja
walk it off and go
jalani saja
dahlah saja, oh, dahlah saja
walk it off and go
jalani saja
mau gimana lagi?
what else can you do?
walau kadang mati rasa
when your feelings are barely there
bahkan hingga tak berdaya
up to a point of pure despair
dan usaha-mu terasa sia-sia
when you have given it your all, but ends in vain
jika memang
just let it go,
jawaban tak kau dapatkan
the answer you've been looking for
jangan tangisi
no need to be sad about it,
coba lalui teka-tekinya
just try to get through your day
relakan lah
just let it go,
karena pada akhirnya
then maybe in the end you'll know
kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
you got what it takes to get through the ache and still win the day
lepas semua kendali
let life take over the wheel
tancap gas dan berlari
and shift it to higher gears
terima dan sudahi
then you will finally see
jika memang
just let it go,
jawaban tak kau dapatkan
the answer you've been looking for
jangan tangisi,
no need to be sad about it,
coba lalui
just try to get through
teka-tekinya
your day
relakan lah,
just let it go,
karena pada akhirnya
then maybe in the end you'll know
kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
you got what it takes to get through the ache and still win the day
dahlah saja, oh, dahlah saja
walk it off and go
jalani saja
dahlah saja, oh, dahlah saja
walk it off and go
jalani saja
まぁいっか
whatever
Comic Frontier！こんばんは！
Comic Frontier! Good evening!
こんばんは！
Good evening!
ようこそ…
Welcome to...
「hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future」へ！
hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future!
やばいやばい
This is crazy, crazy!
5周年のライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much everyone for coming to our 5th anniversary live!
まさかもう5周年とは！
I can't believe it's already been 5 years!
じゃあ自己紹介から始めましょうか？まずはゼータから！
Well then, shall we start with introductions? First is Zeta!
はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes!
よし…あっ後ろか
Alright... Oh, I should step back?
アアア！ミッションスタート！
Ah! Mission start!
スタート！ホロライブインドネシア3期生のベスティア・ゼータです！よろしくお願いします！
Start! I am Vestia Zeta from hololive Indonesia Gen 3! Pleased to meet you!
よろしくゼータ！
Nice to meet you, Zeta!
よし 次はカエラ！
Alright, next is Kaela!
はいはい！カエラ！毎日鍛冶をやってるホロライブインドネシア3期生の鍛冶屋、カエラ・コヴァルスキアです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Kaela! I am Kaela Kovalskia, the blacksmith of hololive Indonesia Gen 3 who grinds every day! Nice to meet you all!
よろしくカエラ！
Nice to meet you, Kaela!
次はこぼだ！こぼ！
Next is Kobo! Kobo!
やっほー！ぽこぽこ〜こぼ・かなえる、アットユアサービス！
Yaa-hoo! Boko-boko~ Kobo Kanaeru, at your service!
君の日々を照らす太陽になりましょう！えへ！
Let me be your sun to shine your day! Ehe!
Kobokers声上げて！
Kobokers, make some noise!
3人で…
And together we are...
ホロライブインドネシア3期生、holoh3roでーす！
hololive Indonesia Gen 3, holoh3ro!
やぁ ついにホロライブID5周年ライブができるとはね
Wow, I can't believe we can finally have a hololive ID 5th anniversary live.
一曲目からもうめっちゃカッコいいよね！その熱気、感じてるわ！
Starting with the very first song, it's already so cool! We can really feel the heat!
やばいっすね
That's crazy, right?
アドレナリンがわいてくるんだもん
これ走りたくなるっすね
Adrenaline is pumping!
It makes me want to run!
おいおいおい どこ行くの？
Hey, hey, hey, where are you going?
いやいやストップストップ！
No, no, stop, stop, stop!
汗かくよ！汗！
You'll sweat! Sweat!
カエラはどう？
How about you, Kaela?
わあ、すごく楽しい
まさか自分がここに立てるとは思わなかったよ
Wow, it's so much fun.
I never thought I'd be standing here.
でもちなみにライブはまだまだ長いから
最後まで張り切っていこうね！
But by the way, the concert is still long,
so let's stay pumped until the end!
張り切ろう！
Let's do this!
でもさっきからライブの話してるけど
みんなライブのタイトル知ってる？
We've been talking about the live, but
does everyone know the title of this concert?
今回のライブは題して
「Chromatic Future」！
The title of this concert is
"Chromatic Future"!
意味わかる人？手を挙げて！
Anyone know what it means? Raise your hand!
こぼが絶対知ってるね
Kobo definitely knows, right?
そうですね、一番背が高い人が説明するっす！
Right, the tallest person should explain it!
そう来るかい！まあいいか
Oh, is that how it is? Well, okay then.
初めての人も聞いてね
For those of you who don't know yet, listen up.
「Chromatic Future」ってのは
カラフルな未来ってことだよ！
"Chromatic Future" means
a colorful future!
ホロライブインドネシアは
もう5周年になるからね
Since Hololive Indonesia is celebrating
its 5th anniversary,
私たちはみんなデビューから今日まで
一緒に歩んできたわけ！
we have walked together
from day one until today!
それでこれから先も、私たちがカラフルな
時間と思い出を創り出せたらいいなってこと
And for the future, we hope to create
colorful times and memories...
もちろんホロライブインドネシアのファンとも一緒に！
...together with all the fans of Hololive Indonesia, of course!
そうっすよ、カエラ・コヴァルスキア！メモってね！
That's right, Kaela Kovalskia! Take notes!
そうそうそう
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
きて、皆さんもうわかりましたよね？
さっきカエラが説明したから
Now, you all understand it, right?
Since Kaela just explained it.
ってことでライブも始まってることだし
And since the concert has already started,
本日のライブのことをSNSに投稿する際は
when you post about today's concert on social media,
ハッシュタグ #holoIDChromaticFuture を
忘れずに付けてくださいわ！
don't forget to use the hashtag
#holoIDChromaticFuture!
だってみんなのその…なんていうの、えっと…
情熱！が見たいから！
Because we really want to see your...
what do you call it, uh... passion!
そうっす！そうっすね！
Yes! That's right!
打ち間違えないでね！
Make sure not to typo!
いえー！絶対投稿してね！
Yeah! Make sure to post!
でも正直に言って
「インドネシアライブやるんだよ！」って
言われた時びっくりした？
But honestly,
were you surprised when they told us
we were going to have a live concert in Indonesia?
もしもし？聞いてくれる？
Hello? Are you listening?
そうっすね！
Yeah!
そうっ！あたしも同感！
妹のセータに共感しているっす
Right! I agree!
I empathize with my little sister Zeta!
そうね、共感ね
Yes, empathy.
カエラ・コヴァルスキアはどう？
How about you, Kaela Kovalskia?
私もびっくりしたよ
なんかこう「え？マジで？」って感じ
I didn't expect it either at the time,
I was like, "Huh? Really?"
なんかこう「え！ついにインドネシアで
9人そろってライブできるんだ！」って！
マジかっこいいよね！
Like, "Wow! Finally,
all nine of us can perform together in Indonesia!"
It's so cool!
かっこいいっす！
はい、これが初めてホロライブインドネシアの
9人全員でのライブだから
Yes, since this is the very first concert with
all nine members of Hololive Indonesia,
実はこれはホロライブインドネシアのファンに
とても重要な瞬間でもあるんだけど
it's actually a very important and major moment
for Hololive Indonesia fans,
世界中のみんなも見てくれるんでしょう？
but everyone all over the world is watching too, right?
ね？
Right?
お答えて
Answer us!
はいはい！みんなありがとう！
Yes, yes! Thank you, everyone!
でももちろんこれで終わりってわけじゃないよね？
But of course,
this achievement doesn't stop here, right?
だから次はこう…世界征服ってのはどう？
So next, how about we... dominate the world?
我々はレディー！レディー！
We are ready! Ready!
レディーレディー！
Ready, ready!
そうっすよカエラ！ゼータ！
That's right, Kaela! Zeta!
この機会におけるファンの支援に加えて
In addition to the support from the fans
on this occasion,
このライブを実現させるために支援いただいた
スポンサーの皆様にも感謝を申し上げまーす！
we'd also like to thank all the sponsors
who supported us in making this concert happen!
ありがとうっす！
Thank you!
ありがとう！みんなありがとうね！
サンキューサンキュー！
Thank you! Thank you, everyone!
Thank you, thank you!
ところでこのライブって
何か違うところあるのかな？
By the way, is there something
different about this concert?
カエラ気付いた？一番気が利くから
Kaela, did you notice?
Since you're the most observant.
もちろんだよ
こぼは気づかないと思うけど
Of course I did.
I don't think Kobo would notice, though.
これだよ
Look at this.
私たちの身体いつもとちょっと違うんだよ
Our models are a bit different than usual.
かわいい！クルクル！
So cute! Spin around!
かわいいかわいい！
So cute, so cute!
カメラこっち！こっち向けて！こっちこっち！
Camera over here! Face here! Here, here!
ほらほら！こぼのかわいさを見て！
これこれ、お尻
Look, look! See Kobo's cuteness!
Look, my butt!
えー！う、え、え、え
Eh! Wh- What?!
おいおいおい
こぼがカメラ全部乗っ取ってるじゃん
Hey, hey, hey,
Kobo is taking over the entire camera!
こっちにも向けてよ こぼだけには向けないで
Point it over here too! Don't just point it at Kobo!
いち、に、さーん…
はい終わり！こぼの番っす！
One, two, three... okay, done! My turn!
ストップストップ！やめてって！
Stop, stop! Cut it out!
カメラ全部乗っ取らないでよ！
Don't take over the whole camera!
はいはい…それじゃあ
Okay, okay... in that case,
やばいちょっと息切れた
Oh dear, I'm a bit out of breath.
ライブではしゃがない！
Don't go too wild during the concert!
はーい
Okay~
はいはい
Yes, yes.
はいよ ゼータが怒ると怖いからね
Sure thing. Because Zeta is scary when she's mad.
はいよ　ゼータが怒ると怖いからね
Alright, because it's scary when Zeta gets angry.
こわいよー
So scary~
もういいや ゼータがカメラを独り占めしちゃダメっていうのなら… うーん、しょうがない
Fine, if Zeta can't monopolize the camera... sigh, it can't be helped.
ファンのみんなと遊ぼう！
Let's play with all the fans!
さっきみんなからも大きな声をもらったわけだし今度はこぼがみんなに大きな声を出したいっす！
We got a huge cheer from everyone earlier, so this time Kobo wants to cheer for everyone!
はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes.
そうっすよ、カエラの配信時間ほど長くはならないから安心して
That's right, it won't be as long as Kaela's stream time, so rest assured!
そう！みんなにじゃなく、みんなとね
Yes! Not to them, but with them.
そうそう！そういうことっす！
Yeah, yeah! That's exactly it!
だってこれから歌わなきゃいけないからまず声を温存しなきゃでしょ？
Because we have to sing after this, so we should save our voices first, right?
そうっすよ、そんなにカエラの配信時間ほど長くはならないから安心して
That's right, it won't be as long as Kaela's stream time, so don't worry.
まあいい　大声出していいから好きにして
Oh well, you can shout if you want, do whatever you like.
みんな準備はいいかな？
Is everyone ready?
もう出来てるみたいっすね！じゃあこぼから！
Looks like you're all ready! Then Kobo goes first!
一緒に「BOKOBOKOBO！」って叫ぼう！よし、いくよ！
Let's shout "BOKOBOKOBO!" together! Alright, here we go!
いち、に、さん！
One, two, three!
BOKOBOKOBO！
BOKOBOKOBO!
いいねいいね！次はゼータ！
Nice, nice! Next is Zeta!
「ミッションスタート！」って言ったら一緒に「スタート！」って言ってね！
When I say "Mission Start!", say "Start!" together with me!
いいか？アアア！ミッション…
Ready? Ah-ah-ah! Mission...
スタート！
Start!
次はカエラ！
Next is Kaela!
よしよし！きてみんな　そしてholoh3roも
Alright, alright! Come on everyone, and holoh3ro too.
「holoh3ro！」って言ったら「HU-HA！」で返してね！簡単でしょう？
When I say "holoh3ro!", reply with "HU-HA!". Easy, right?
さあさあさあさあ！
Come on, come on, come on!
準備はいい？holoh3ro！
Are you ready? holoh3ro!
HU-HA！
HU-HA!
いいねいいねいいね！
Nice, nice, nice!
いいわついに３期生は息ぴったり
Great, the 3rd generation is finally in perfect sync!
そうわまだまだ元気がありそうだね
Yeah, looks like everyone is still full of energy.
だって、今日の一曲目だけでもうすごく伝わってくるんだもん
Because even with just our first song today, we could really feel it.
みんなまさか私たちの一曲目が「100％」だなんて思ってた？
Did anyone expect our first song to be "100%"?
思うわけないよな　私もびっくりした
No way anyone would've expected that. I was surprised too!
ホシノヴァ気分でライブ開始だなんて！すごいのよね？
Starting the live with a Hoshinova vibe! It was amazing, right?
やばい！
Crazy!
かっこいいっすね、しかもさっきゼータとかが歌った… いや違う
It was so cool, and also when Zeta sang earlier... wait, no.
ゼータとかが？
Zeta sang?
ゼータとカエラが歌った時はもう本家の「100％」みたいっす
When Zeta and Kaela sang, it was just like the original "100%"!
マジかっこよすぎるんだけどなんか、うーう！ってなってき！
It was seriously too cool, it made me go "urgh! urgh!"
あんなかっこいい歌を歌ったことあるのかな？
I wonder if you've ever sung such a cool song before?
かっこつけてんの？
Are you acting cool?
そう、かっこつけてる　本物のかっこつけだってムーナの曲かっこいいもん
Yeah, acting cool, for real. Moona's songs are just so cool.
だってゼータがいつもスタイリッシュとかジャズっぽい曲ばっかしょ？
Because Zeta always sings stylish or jazzy songs, right?
だからさっき「100％」を歌った時めっちゃ雰囲気が違う
So when she sang "100%" earlier, the vibe was completely different.
しかもカエラのラップも！
And Kaela's rap too!
なんかこう…
It was like...
とにかくかっこよかった！すごいわ！
Anyway, it was so cool! Amazing!
そうね
Yeah, indeed.
でも、それだけじゃないよ！次の曲が「NEW zomBIE!!」でした！
But that's not all! The next song was "NEW zomBIE!!"!
これだれの曲かわかるよね？
You know whose song this is, right?
もちろんだよ　うちの先輩だ
Of course we do, it's our senpai's!
holoroのパフォーマンスもめちゃかっこよかったよまるでゲームの中にいるみたいだった
holoro's performance was also super cool, it felt like being inside a game.
そうっすわ！しかもバックダンサーもいたし
That's right! And they even had back dancers!
かっこよかったっすね！
It was so cool!
他になんかあったかな？レーザーも花火も！あと…
What else was there? Lasers, fireworks! And...
すごいギミックがたくさんあったっすね！
There were so many awesome stage gimmicks!
あのバックダンサーたちあたしのソロライブに雇うっす
I'm going to hire those back dancers for my solo concert.
おっと、もうソロライブの話？
Whoa, talking about a solo concert already?
まあ言葉も祈りってやつ
Well, words are like prayers after all.
でもこのライブはまだ終わらないよ！まだまだ！
But this concert isn't over yet! Far from it!
でも…さっき何の歌を歌ったか知ってる？
But... do you know what song we sang just before this?
もちろんだよ　私の新しい曲だから
Of course I do, since it's my new song.
そうっすね
That's right.
まあいいや
Oh well.
いやいや！タイトルは「dahlah.」だよ！「dahlah.」！
No, no! The title is "dahlah."! "dahlah."!
おおなるほど
Oh, I see!
「dahlah.」だったか…まあわざとだったけど
So it was "dahlah."... Well, I knew that.
だっていつもそれ言ってるじゃん本当にまあいいやと思ってた
Because you always say that, so I thought you literally meant "oh well"!
それ言って帰ると思ってた
I thought you were saying that and going home.
いやいや、かわいそうだから
No, no, that would be sad.
じゃあ「dahlah」ってどういう意味？
Then, what does "dahlah" mean?
人生はしょうがないって意味
It means "life is what it is / there's no helping it."
人生は重いからまあいいやって言えばいいだけ
Life is heavy, so you just say "whatever".
その後人生を続けようって意味
And then keep moving forward with life.
そうっすね、大人になったらね
That's right, once we grow up.
Dan lagu... ya santai, easy listening, jadi kita sambil keliling-keliling kan nyapa fans gitu ya.
Luckily, the song is relaxing and easy listening, so we can walk around and greet the fans, right?
Asyik banget ya tadi ya? Aku juga suka banget tadi dansa bagian reff-nya ya.
It was so fun, right? I also really liked the dance during the chorus!
Itu, itu beda lagu gak sih? Gak gitu deh...
Wait, isn't that a different song? I don't think it's like that.
Tapi, pokoknya asyik lah ya kalau nyanyi lagu chill santai-santai kayak gini.
But anyway, it's really fun to sing a chill and relaxing song like this.
Iya, santai dong.
Yeah, relaxing.
Tapi, ngomongin soal santai, kita tuh sebenarnya belum bisa santai dulu. Hei, santai!
But speaking of relaxing, we actually can't relax just yet. Hey, relax!
Kayaknya katanya gak boleh santai-santai. Jangan terlalu santai!
I heard we're not allowed to relax. Don't be too relaxed!
Karena Konsernya tuh masih panjang!
Because the concert is still far from over!
Jadi, sebelum itu, kalian ada gak yang mau kalian sampaikan dulu? Mulai dari ini nih, yang gak bisa diam.
So before that, is there anything you'd like to say first? Starting from this talkative one here!
Tiga kata saja... I love you.
Just three words... I love you.
Keren! The best! Sangat jelas, ya.
Cool! The best! Very clear, indeed.
Tetap semangat, tetap semangat menjalani hidup, ya. Udah gitu aja. Pokoknya sampai akhir masih panjang. Semangat!
Keep your spirits up, keep going strong in life. That's all. Anyway, it's still a long way to the end. Fighting!
Saranghaeyo! Gomawoyo!
I love you! Thank you!
Oke, kalau aku, ya... Semangat selalu! Semangat santai! Hidup jangan terlalu dibawa serius.
Okay, as for me... Always stay spirited! Spirited yet relaxed! Don't take life too seriously.
Semangat santai, ya? / Semangat santai!
Spirited and relaxed, huh? / Spirited and relaxed!
Oke, kalau gitu kita lanjutkan! / Hei, hei, hei! Tunggu dulu!
Alright, if so, let's continue! / Hey, hey, hey! Wait a minute!
Sebelum selesai-selesai ini nih ya, kita teriak bareng-bareng penonton dulu gak sih?
Before we finish all of this, shouldn't we scream together with the audience first?
Iya dong! Ayo! Ayo! Ayo!
Yes, of course! Let's do it! Let's go!
Oke, oke. Jadi, kita teriak bareng ya, dalam hitungan ketiga kita sama-sama teriak "Chromatic Future", oke ya?
Okay, okay. So, let's scream together. On the count of three, we'll all scream "Chromatic Future", okay?
Oke, oke. "Chromatic Future" gitu kan ya? / Iya, iya, kayak gitu, kayak gitu.
Okay, okay. Like "Chromatic Future!", right? / Yes, yes, just like that.
Oke, langsung ya! Sambil lihat... Sini, sini, sini, sambil lihat! / Aku ya, aku, aku, aku yang penonton ini, penonton sini.
Okay, let's do it! Look... Here, here, look over here! / I'll do this side of the audience, over here.
Iya, iya, oke, berarti aku yang tengah, yang tengah. Halo!
Yeah, yeah, okay, then I'll take the middle. Hello!
Oke, bareng-bareng ya! Satu, dua, tiga!
Okay, together now! One, two, three!
Chromatic Future!
Everything was easy, I did it all alone
So effortlessly
I spread my wings and let my magic unfold
Got all problems solved
Without any setbacks, there is nothing uncontrolled
But there's no way I can begin
Dream life that I need to win
I need to feel how all these things crumble into little pieces
I know I gotta soar a little higher
Hope all turns to be the things I desire
Layaknya burung merak yang bersayap
Like a winged peacock,
'Kan 'ku taklukkan gelap
I will conquer the darkness.
Dengan sihir angin 'kan 'ku ajak
With the magic of wind, I will invite
Semua yang terlelap 'tuk bangkit melawan dunia
everyone who is asleep to rise up and face the world.
We'll never give up
As long as we got the strength in ourselves
We could rise above the pain
We're stronger than them
Walking step by step, trusting my own pace
Giving me what I deserve to have
Let's go, just believe me
Let it go
They'll never bring me down, just believe me
It'll never bring us down, just believe me
Won't let their cruelty steal my royalty
And when the universe works against me, I will just
Let it go! If it's spicy, just sip some tea, let it go!
Let it go
I've been living carefree
There's no bitter words in the world that could affect me
I spread my wings and let my magic unfold
Not letting it show
Stings, but I'm bigger than my feelings, so that'll be enough
There is no way I can begin
Dream life that I need to win
I need to feel how all these things crumble into little pieces
I know I gotta be better than ever
Hope all turns to be sweeter than ever
Layaknya burung merak yang bersayap
Like a winged peacock,
'Kan 'ku taklukkan gelap
I will conquer the darkness.
Dengan sihir angin 'kan 'ku ajak
With the magic of wind, I will invite
Semua yang terlelap 'tuk bangkit...
everyone who is asleep to rise up...
...melawan dunia
...against the world
We'll never give up!
As long as we got the strength in ourselves
We could rise above the pain
We're stronger than them
Walking step by step
Trusting by our pace
Giving me what I deserve to have
Let's go!
Believe me, let it go
They'll never bring me down, just believe me
Let it go
It'll never bring us down, just believe me
Won't let their cruelty
Steal all my royalty
And when the universe is against me, I will just...
...let it go
Let it go!
Come on guys, let's do this!
One, two, three, let it go!
Let it go!
hololive indonesia CHROMATIC FUTURE 5th Anniversary LIVE